<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zumafi Surgery on Surgeons Aid ☘️</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zumafi Surgery on Surgeons Aid ☘️</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:44:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>⛑️ Bleeding per rectum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/gi/bleeding-pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/gi/bleeding-pr/</guid>
      <description>Bleeding per Rectum History # Bleeding per Rectum # Onset &amp;amp; Duration Colour Bright red Altered Mixed (fresh + altered) → PPV higher when dark and bright mixed blood than dark or bright blood alone Melena (Sticky, blackish, difficult to flush) Timing with Defecation Before Mixed (towards malignancy) Streaky (fissure, low rectal CA) After Dribbling Spurting Amount? Cup/diapers/clots Any Other Bleeding Manifestations Associated Anal Pain? Fissure, abscess, hematoma, anal carcinoma Uncomplicated hemorrhoids or rectal cancer are not usually painful Any Lump at Anus?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🐢 Tracheostomy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/anatomy/tracheostomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/anatomy/tracheostomy/</guid>
      <description>Surgical Anatomy of Tracheostomy: A Detailed Exploration # Tracheostomy, a surgical procedure involving the creation of an opening into the trachea through the neck, is a critical intervention in various medical contexts, from emergency airway management to long-term ventilation support. Understanding the intricate anatomy of the neck and the layered dissection involved is paramount for safe and effective tracheostomy placement.&#xA;Anatomical Considerations # 1. Surface Anatomy: Tracheostomy is typically performed between the second and fourth tracheal rings, corresponding to the level of the cricoid cartilage (C6 vertebrae level).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>👒 Bladder CA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/genitourinary/bladder-ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/genitourinary/bladder-ca/</guid>
      <description>Haematuria History # True Haematuria or Not # Exact Color: Dark tea color (OJ) Exclude Pseudohaematuria: Itching &amp;amp; steatorrhoea Factitious Haematuria: Munchausen’s syndrome, narcotic seeking behavior Past History # Bleeding diathesis &amp;amp; other bleeding manifestations Relation of Gross Haematuria to Urinary Stream # Initial (urethra distal to urogenital diaphragm) Total (bladder proper or upper urinary tract) Terminal (trigone/ bladder neck of prostatic urethra) Painless or Painful # Painless: Malignant but can cause pain due to clot colics Painful: Urinary tract infection or calculus, papillary necrosis, passage of clots, obstruction, loin-pain haematuria syndrome, glomerulonephritis Clots # Indicate non-glomerular bleeding Large, thick, irregular clots - bladder Small, linear clots - upper tract Passage of tissues Associated Symptoms # LUTS Fever, chills &amp;amp; rigors with loin pain or suprapubic pain Any loin pain with self-felt loin lumps (Classic triad of RCC 10% - haematuria+loin pain+loin mass) Tissue passage Vaginal or penile discharge, sexual activity Presence of urinary catheter Relation to menstruation (endometriosis) Anemic symptoms GU History # History of BPH, stone disease (Hx of GU cancers) Hx of instrumentation Hx of pelvic irradiation Aetiology for Malignancies # Smoking Occupational exposure to dye stuffs and rubber compounds Hx of travel to middle east countries (Schistosoma haematobium) Family history malignancy (bleeding diathesis + renal disease) Metastatic Features # Fitness for Sx PMHx- # PSHx- # Drug Hx- # Antiplatelets or anticoagulants, cyclophosphamide SHx- # Job(risk factors)/family Smoking/alcohol Disability/concerns Examination # General # Anemia/plethora Facial oedema/ periorbital oedema, rather than ankle edema suggest renal pathology Unilateral or bilateral ankle edema- think of Iliac vein compression in unilateral edema Bone tenderness Muscle weakness Malignant cachexia- anaemia asthenia anorexia Ask for BP Abdomen # Palpable suprapubic mass- distended bladder, anterior wall bladder tumor Ballotable renal mass Hepatomegaly Ascites DRE &amp;amp; genital Ex (non-reducing left varicocele) Summary # This 60 yrs old ASA 2, MET score &amp;gt;4, male patient with episodic visible haematuria over 3 months associated with occasional clots &amp;amp; passage of tissues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Surgery 🚀</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/core/principles-of-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/core/principles-of-surgery/</guid>
      <description>At me ipso nepotibus nunc celebratior genus # Tanto oblite # Copy to Clipboard {{ emojify &amp;ldquo;&amp;#x270c;&amp;#xfe0f;&amp;rdquo; }} {{ &amp;ldquo;Hello! &amp;#x1f44b;&amp;rdquo; | .RenderString }} Lorem markdownum pectora novis patenti igne sua opus aurae feras materiaque illic demersit imago et aristas questaque posset. Vomit quoque suo inhaesuro clara. Esse cumque, per referri triste. Ut exponit solisque communis in tendens vincetis agisque iamque huic bene ante vetat omina Thebae rates. Aeacus servat admonitu concidit, ad resimas vultus et rugas vultu dignamque Siphnon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Surgery 🚀</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/principles/principles-of-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/principles/principles-of-surgery/</guid>
      <description>At me ipso nepotibus nunc celebratior genus # Tanto oblite # Copy to Clipboard {{ emojify &amp;ldquo;&amp;#x270c;&amp;#xfe0f;&amp;rdquo; }} {{ &amp;ldquo;Hello! &amp;#x1f44b;&amp;rdquo; | .RenderString }} Lorem markdownum pectora novis patenti igne sua opus aurae feras materiaque illic demersit imago et aristas questaque posset. Vomit quoque suo inhaesuro clara. Esse cumque, per referri triste. Ut exponit solisque communis in tendens vincetis agisque iamque huic bene ante vetat omina Thebae rates. Aeacus servat admonitu concidit, ad resimas vultus et rugas vultu dignamque Siphnon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surgery Topics 🔪✂🪡💉</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/hid_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/hid_index/</guid>
      <description> Welcome to Our Surgery Portal 🏥 # </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operative surgery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/core/operative-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/core/operative-surgery/</guid>
      <description>Caput vino delphine in tamen vias # Cognita laeva illo fracta # Lorem markdownum pavent auras, surgit nunc cingentibus libet Laomedonque que est. Pastor An arbor filia foedat, ne fugit aliter, per. Helicona illas et callida neptem est Oresitrophos caput, dentibus est venit. Tenet reddite famuli praesentem fortibus, quaeque vis foret si frondes gelidos gravidae circumtulit inpulit armenta nativum.&#xA;Te at cruciabere vides rubentis manebo Maturuit in praetemptat ruborem ignara postquam habitasse Subitarum supplevit quoque fontesque venabula spretis modo Montis tot est mali quasque gravis Quinquennem domus arsit ipse Pellem turis pugnabant locavit Natus quaerere # Pectora et sine mulcere, coniuge dum tincta incurvae.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operative surgery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/principles/operative-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/principles/operative-surgery/</guid>
      <description>Caput vino delphine in tamen vias # Cognita laeva illo fracta # Lorem markdownum pavent auras, surgit nunc cingentibus libet Laomedonque que est. Pastor An arbor filia foedat, ne fugit aliter, per. Helicona illas et callida neptem est Oresitrophos caput, dentibus est venit. Tenet reddite famuli praesentem fortibus, quaeque vis foret si frondes gelidos gravidae circumtulit inpulit armenta nativum.&#xA;Te at cruciabere vides rubentis manebo Maturuit in praetemptat ruborem ignara postquam habitasse Subitarum supplevit quoque fontesque venabula spretis modo Montis tot est mali quasque gravis Quinquennem domus arsit ipse Pellem turis pugnabant locavit Natus quaerere # Pectora et sine mulcere, coniuge dum tincta incurvae.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🍁 Breast CA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/breastendo/breastca/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 12:44:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/breastendo/breastca/</guid>
      <description>Breast cancer long case # History # %%{init: {&#39;theme&#39;: &#39;dark&#39;}}%% mindmap root((Breast Hx)) HPC Lump Main lump Other lump Nipple discharge Breast pain DD TB Trauma RF Hormone Endo Menarche/Menopause 1st Preg/Lactation Nulliparity Exo OCP HRT Lifestyle CMLx Local Systemic UptoNow Ix NAT HPC # About the main breast lump How did you 1st notice the lump? Progression of the lump Associated symptoms – pain, alteration of nipple, discharge Other lumps Is there any lump on opposite breast or axilla?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>⚙️ Other resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/otherresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/otherresources/</guid>
      <description> Resources # Youtube PG classes # 🍄 General Surgery PG Clinics ⛑️ General Surgery PG masterclass 👨🏽‍🎓 Surgery by Prof. Chintamani 🌼 Surgery Short cases 💐 Surgery Exam cases 🪢 Surgery Exam Essay papers # 📚 Download All Essay Past papers Click here&#xA;Essay papers by year # MD (Surgery) Examination - 2023 [September/October] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2023 [March] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2022 [October] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2022 [March] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2021 [November] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2021 [February] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2020 [September] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2020 [February] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2019 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2019 [February] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2018 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2018 [Jan/Feb] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2017 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2017 [February] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2016 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2016 [February] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2015 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2015 [February] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2014 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2014 [January] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2013 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2013 [February] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2012 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2012 [February] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2011 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2011 [January] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2010 [July] MD (Surgery) Examination - 2010 [January] </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🧠 Tumours of the Central Nervous System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tumoursofcns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 20:44:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tumoursofcns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;prognosis&lt;/strong&gt; for a brain tumour diagnosis remains poor. - The three &lt;strong&gt;most common&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;brain tumours&lt;/em&gt; are - meningiomas - Most common brain tumor - Glioma is the most commonly operated brain tumour. - and cerebral metastases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🏵️ SL Breast Guideline Summary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/slbreastguidelinesummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:44:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/slbreastguidelinesummary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;triple assessment&lt;/strong&gt; of clinical examination, imaging, and histopathology remains the cornerstone of the diagnostic work-up in patients suspected to have breast cancer. - Obtain a full history and perform a complete general examination, including an examination of the breasts, axillae, and supraclavicular fossae.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🌸 Mastectomy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/operative/breastendocrine/mastectomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/operative/breastendocrine/mastectomy/</guid>
      <description>MASTECTOMY # Pre-operative # Consent # Discuss reconstruction options. Present alternatives (e.g., Breast-Conserving Surgery). Inform about post-operative chemotherapy and radiotherapy. Explain potential post-operative complications. Pre-operative Ward Preparation # Mark the surgical site. Mark the incision in the supine position and verify in the sitting position. Ensure 1 pint of blood is ready. Shave the axilla. In the Theatre # Preparation # WHO safety checklist. Position patient supine arm abducted at 90 degrees on an arm board, with a sandbag under the ipsilateral scapula.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🌸 Short Case Topics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/shortcasetopics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/shortcasetopics/</guid>
      <description> Short Case topics # Upper Limb # Axillary lumps Claw hand Dequervain&amp;rsquo;s Tenosynovitis Elbow lumps Forearm lumps Nerve injuries Wrist drop Wrist lumps ganglion Subungual lesions Lower Limb # AV malformation - popliteal fossa Bunion Buttock, thigh, and calf lumps CTEV (Congenital Talipes Equinovarus) Femoral hernia Foot ulcer Genu valgus Ingrowing toenail Knee lumps Neuropathic sole ulcer Slipped upper femoral epiphysis Neck # Anterior triangle lump (Carotid triangle / sternomastoid) Carotid body tumour CDH (Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia) Cervical rib Goitre / solitary nodule Midline neck lump Posterior triangle lump Submandibular lump Suprasternal / supraclavicular lump Chest and Abdominal Wall # Chest wall lesions Pancoast lump Vesicular eruptions of chest Abdominal mass Incisional hernia Inguinal hernia PUH (Paraumbilical Hernia) Hand and Wrist # Mallet finger Pointing index Tendon injuries Volkmann&amp;rsquo;s ischaemic contracture Wasting of small muscles Head and Face # Carcinoma of maxillary sinus Facial lumps Parotid lump Proptosis Retension cyst in the mouth Scalp lump - bony / soft Oral / tongue ulcer Breast and Trunk # Breast lump / gynaecomastia Hydradenitis Bone and Joint # Bone tumour Complicated fracture POP (Plaster of Paris) External fixator Myositis ossificans Osteosarcoma Amputation stump Halux valgus Skin and Soft Tissue # Bursae Cystic hygroma Dermoid cyst Digital gangrene Dry gangrene Hydradenitis Keloid / hypertrophic scar Lipoma Neurofibroma Sebaceous cyst Skin lesions - melanoma/squamous ca/basal cell ca Soft Tissue Sarcoma External angular lumps Vascular # False aneurysm Pseudoaneurysm / AVF Varicose veins Genitourinary # Penile CA (Carcinoma) Scrotal lump - Hydrocele, epididymal cyst Scrotal lump - spermatocele, varicocele, tumour Undescended testes Cryptorchidism </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🌼 Long Case Topics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/longcasetopics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/longcasetopics/</guid>
      <description> Longcase Topics # GI # Anaemia Anorexia &amp;amp; weight loss Bleeding PR / Altered bowel habits / Malaena with SOB Dyspeptic symptoms / epigastric pain Dysphagia - achalasia of cardia / Ca oesophagus / Benign strictures Enterocutaneous fistula Epigastric / RHC mass - Liver Ca, Pancreas CA, Pseudocyst, Gastric CA Haematemesis / malaena / Portal hypertension Intestinal obstruction Obstructive jaundice - Gall stones / CA pancreas / Strictures / compression RIF / LIF mass Stomach - carcinoma / PUD Vascular # Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm Chronic limb ulcer PVD Unilateral limb swelling POAD - Peripheral occlusive arterial disease Onco Breast Thyroid # Backache / Low back pain Breast CA - axillary lumps Goitre / Solitary nodule Cancer of unknown primary (CUP) - Cervical LN, Bone Iiry, Liver mets, ascites, pathological fracture GU # Haematuria Loin mass / pain LUTS / BPH Urinary fistula Young hypertensive </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🍔 Common Topics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/commontopics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/commontopics/</guid>
      <description> Common Topics # Trauma # Blunt trauma - abdomen Chest trauma Chest wall and contents - injury Crush injury - pelvis Haematuria following blunt trauma ITU - indications for managing a surgical patient ITU - indications for nursing a patient in Missile injury - limb: neurovascular bundle intact Stab injury - trunk General Surgery # Abdominal Surgery # Abdominal TB CBD Stone - Modern Management Cholecystitis - Aetiology and Diagnosis Large Bowel Obstruction - Malignant, Management of Low Urine Output 24 Hours After Major Abdominal Surgery Pancreatitis - Acute, Complications Sigmoid Volvulus Hernias # Femoral Hernia - Strangulated Incisional Hernias - Factors That Influence the Development Inguinal Hernia Repair - Laparoscopic Method Neck Surgery # Anterior Triangle of the Neck - Lump In Hypotension - Acute Occurring After 3 Days of Block Dissection of the Neck Parotid Area - Differential Diagnosis of Lump In Parotidectomy Consent Submandibular Salivary Gland Swelling Thyroglossal Tract Anomaly Breast &amp;amp; Endocrine Surgery # Lumps in the Breast Solitary Thyroid Nodule Thyroid - Clinically Solitary Nodule Thyroid - Medullary Carcinoma Thyroid Carcinoma Diagnosis Thyroidectomy Complications Urological Surgery # Circumcision Scrotal Swelling in the Adult Torsion of the Testis Wound and Skin Management # Burns - Management Skin Defects Management Ulceration of Finger - One Hand Wound Healing - Factors That Delay Wound Infection - Prevention Trauma and Emergency Surgery # Fall on Outstretched Hand Ventilation - Assisted Role in the Management of Major Trauma Surgical Techniques and Instruments # Biopsy - Techniques with Their Indications and Limitations Diathermy Diathermy - Complications in Open Surgery Laparoscopy in General Surgery Local Anaesthesia - Techniques Used Operating Theatre - Preventing Inadvertent Harm to the Patient OT - Preparation of Surgical Instruments Stents RCT - Principles, Design Surgical Management and Considerations # Audit - Surgical Blood - Minimizing the Use of Bank Blood for Major Surgery Computers in Surgery - Role of Day Case Surgery - AD/DA Ethical Committee - Composition and Function MRSA - Steps to Be Taken in Managing in the Ward Surgical Operation - Factors Contributing to a Shorter Hospital Stay Postoperative Care # Haemorrhage Post-Op Complications Pyrexia - Post-Op Gastrointestinal Symptoms and Issues # Dysphagia - Diagnosis and Causes Perianal Pain - Diagnosis and Management Rectal Bleeding - Fresh Miscellaneous # CTS HIV/HBV Infection Precautions When Operating On Immunosuppressive Therapy Radioisotope Bone Scanning - Diagnostic Uses Salivary Calculi Ulnar Nerve Injury - Causes and Clinical Features Cardiac Problem Assessment in a Patient Needing Major Surgery GI Surgery # Anal fissure Anal pain in adults Anastomotic breakdown - GI - factors affecting Bowel diseases - inflammatory, irritable Colonic diverticular disease Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease GI tract manifestations Gastrointestinal bleeding - methods of localizing GI haemorrhage - arrest of GORD Haematemesis Pancreatic neoplasms - non-endocrine presentation Pancreatitis - acute, assessment of severity GU Surgery # Haematuria Prostate cancer - presentation Renal - unilateral hydronephrosis / hydroureter Ureter in solitary kidney - management of obstruction Urethra - rupture of the membranous urethra Urethral catheterization - long-term sequelae Urinary incontinence - mechanisms Urinary retention - acute Urological investigation - ultrasound in Urological investigations - place for ultrasound Undescended testis Neurosurgery # Cerebral metastases EDH Head injury after RTA Oncosurgery # Basal cell carcinoma Breast cancer - adjuvant therapy Breast cancer - female Breast cancer - management of malignant pleural effusions Hypercalcaemia associated with malignant disease In situ cancer - definition and discussion of examples Malignant melanoma Radiotherapy for cancer - complications Rectal cancer - palliative treatment Teratoma of the testis Tongue and cheek - leukoplakia Orthopedic Surgery # Bone metastases - diagnosis of Closed fracture Colles fracture Complicated femoral fracture Compound complicated fracture Femoral fracture proximal 1/3 in the elderly Fracture - methods of internal fixation Fracture in the lower limb - vascular complications Joint replacement - total - prevention of complications Knee joint - penetrating injury Open midshaft fracture of the tibia Paget&amp;rsquo;s disease of the bone Pyogenic arthritis Radial fracture - distal Shoulder - acute dislocation Shoulder anterior dislocation Spinal injury - T/L junction Supracondylar fracture Supracondylar fracture of the humerus in children Thoracolumbar spinal injury Pediatric Surgery # Airway obstruction - acute in a child CDH in children CTEV DDH (CDH) Inguinal hernia in a 9-month-old boy Pyloric stenosis - congenital hypertrophic Vomiting - projectile Plastic and Thoracic Surgery # Wounds involving significant loss of skin Pneumothorax - spontaneous Vascular Surgery # AAA surgery - common major perioperative complications Amputation of lower limb Angioplasty Arterial insufficiency Varicose veins of the lower limb Cervical rib Duplex scan - role in surgery DVT - complications of False aneurysm Intermittent claudication Ischaemic leg Leg ulcers - diagnosis and assessment excluding treatment Lower limb ischaemia Lower limb - chronic unilateral swelling PVD Trap gun injury - popliteal artery damage Varicose veins Vascular surgery (peripheral) thrombolysis Venous ulcer of the lower limb </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🐡 Operative surgery Topics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/operativesxtopics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/operativesxtopics/</guid>
      <description>General surgery # Abscess # Abscess - breast / parotid / intra-abdominal / perinephric Drainage of pelvic abscess Palmar abscess drainage Pharyngeal abscess drainage Abdominal Procedures # Burst abdomen Fistulectomy Upper GI # Bleeding duodenal ulcer Gastroduodenal perforation Gastrostomy / Gastrojejunostomy / Pyloroplasty Partial gastrectomy Oesophagectomy - approaches Cystogastrostomy Cardiomyotomy Lower GI # Appendicectomy Feeding jejunostomy Ileostomy APR / AR Bowel resection and anastamosis Colostomy Hartmann&amp;rsquo;s procedure Right / Left Hemicolectomy Hepato-Pancreatico-Biliary # Approach to pancreas Pseudopancreatic cyst - cystogastrostomy Whipple&amp;rsquo;s surgery Cholecystectomy Splenectomy Hernia # Femoral hernia - Low / High / Transinguinal Inguinal hernia Inguinal hernia - Bassini / Shouldice / Mesh Strangulated hernia - inguinal / femoral PUH, Incisional hernia - anatomical / Mayo&amp;rsquo;s / Mesh Breast &amp;amp; Thyroid # Breast lump excision Mastectomy Subcutaneous Mastectomy Retrosternal thyroid Thyroidectomy Genitourinary # Circumcision Orchidectomy Orchidopexy Varicocele (Evansvich ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>👢 Cauda equina syndrome, Acute foot drop &amp; neurogenic claudication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/caudaequinafootdropclaudication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/caudaequinafootdropclaudication/</guid>
      <description>Cauda equina syndrome, Acute foot drop &amp;amp; neurogenic claudication # Cauda equina syndrome # Triad of symptoms - Cauda equina syndrome (CESR) is deﬁned as a triad of symptoms including: bilateral lower limb radicular pain perianal sensory loss insensate urinary retention and subsequent incontinence. Often the ﬁrst symptom is the radiculopathy. Urogenital symptoms last.&#xA;Terms&#xA;Cauda equina syndrome (CESR) Cauda equina in evolution (CESE) = A patient progressing through these symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>👹 Radiculopathy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/radiculopathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/radiculopathy/</guid>
      <description>Radiculopathy # Introduction # Radiculopathy is a symptom generated by pathology affecting the nerve roots. Peripheral neuropathy is differentiated from radiculopathy by the distribution of the symptoms. Anatomy # The nerve roots ‘radiate’ from the spinal cord = radiculopathy. The root traverses four zones: the central canal (intrathecal); the lateral recess (within the root sleeve); the foramen; and the extraforaminal space . Pathology # Due to both compression and inflammation - ‘chemical neuroradiculitis’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🦀 Principles of surgery Topics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/principlestopics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/principlestopics/</guid>
      <description>All the topics of Principles of surgery will be asked in the exam.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🌕 Lipoma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/lipoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/lipoma/</guid>
      <description>Often multiple lumps with smooth surface and spherical in shape with distinct irregular curve margins currosponding to the lobes. The &amp;ldquo;slipping sign&amp;rdquo; is not diagnostic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🍇 Pyogenic granuloma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/pyogenicgranuloma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/pyogenicgranuloma/</guid>
      <description>A Hemispherical discharging nodule which grows upwards and outwards following a minor trauma. Initailly bright red, then become pale when it doubles in size just in few days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🎽 Other</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/other/</guid>
      <description> Miscellaneous # AAA Young hypertensive </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>👋 Hand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/hand/</guid>
      <description>Hand # Pointing index Mallet finger Wasting of small muscles Wrist drop Wrist lumps ganglion Claw hand CTS De Quervain&amp;rsquo;s Tenosynovitis Principles of hand examination # Principles include includes inspection palpation Feel Move Range of movement Ease of movement Inspection invisible scars over common surgical sites contour of the hand discoloration and sinuses. Also check muscle wasting, Thenar eminence Hypothenar eminence dorsal side of hand the muscle bulk between metacarpal bones which is interosseous muscle Palpation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>👠 Foot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/foot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/foot/</guid>
      <description> Foot # Halux valgus Ingrowing toenail Bunion </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🏒 Ortho Other</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/otherortho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/otherortho/</guid>
      <description> Other ortho shortcases # Forearm lumps Tendon injuries - Achilles heel Myositis ossificans Nerve injuries Osteosarcoma / bone tumour POP cast Colles/ AK POP Volkmann&amp;rsquo;s ischaemic contracture External fixator Complicated fracture POP </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🤸‍♀️ Limb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/limb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/limb/</guid>
      <description> Limb # Foot ulcer Amputation stump AV malformation popliteal fossa Neuropathic sole ulcer Varicose veins Digital gangrene / Dry gangrene Unilateral limb swelling Chronic limb ulcer Pseudoaneurysm / AVF </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🦕 Neck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/neck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/neck/</guid>
      <description> Neck # Anterior triangle lump (Carotid triangle / sternomastoid) Carotid body tumour </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🧅 Sebaceous Cyst</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/sebaceouscyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/sebaceouscyst/</guid>
      <description>Smooth tense spherical lump with a punctum presents for years. Often Multiple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🦿 Joint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/joints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/joints/</guid>
      <description> Major joints # Genu valgum Knee lumps CDH Limping Child Slipped upper femoral epiphysis CTEV Elbow lumps </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🍄 Dermoid cyst</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/dermoidcyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/dermoidcyst/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/signs/a-signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/signs/a-signs/</guid>
      <description>Signs starts with A # 1. Aaron’s Sign # A sensation of pain and/or distress in the epigastric or precordial region on pressure over McBurney’s point in appendicitis.&#xA;1. Aaron’s Sign # A sensation of pain and/or distress in the epigastric or precordial region on pressure over McBurney’s point in appendicitis.&#xA;2. Abadie’s Sign # Charles Abadie: Spasm of levator palpebrae superioris muscle—a sign of Graves’ disease. Jean Abadie: Insensibility of Achilles tendon to pressure, seen in tabes dorsalis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/signs/b-sign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/signs/b-sign/</guid>
      <description>Signs starts with B # 9. Babinski’s Sign (Not synonymous with Babinski’s Reflex) # a. Loss or weakening of the Achilles tendon reflex in sciatica. This sign helps distinguish true sciatica from hysterical sciatica. 9. Babinski’s Sign (Not synonymous with Babinski’s Reflex) # a. Loss or weakening of the Achilles tendon reflex in sciatica. This sign helps distinguish true sciatica from hysterical sciatica. b. In hemiplegia, the contraction of the platysma muscle on the healthy side is more pronounced than on the affected side.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/hidden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/hidden/</guid>
      <description>This page is hidden in menu # Quondam non pater est dignior ille Eurotas # Latent te facies # Lorem markdownum arma ignoscas vocavit quoque ille texit mandata mentis ultimus, frementes, qui in vel. Hippotades Peleus pennas conscia cuiquam Caeneus quas.&#xA;Pater demittere evincitque reddunt Maxime adhuc pressit huc Danaas quid freta Soror ego Luctus linguam saxa ultroque prior Tatiumque inquit Saepe liquitur subita superata dederat Anius sudor Cum honorum Latona # O fallor in sustinui iussorum equidem.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
