<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zumafi Surgery on Surgeons Aid ☘️</title><link>http://localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content in Zumafi Surgery on Surgeons Aid ☘️</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>⛑️ Bleeding per rectum</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/bleeding-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/bleeding-pr/</guid><description>Bleeding per Rectum History # Bleeding per Rectum # Onset &amp;amp; Duration Colour Bright red Altered Mixed (fresh + altered) → PPV higher when dark and bright mixed blood than dark or bright blood alone Melena (Sticky, blackish, difficult to flush) Timing with Defecation Before Mixed (towards malignancy) Streaky (fissure, low rectal CA) After Dribbling Spurting Amount? Cup/diapers/clots Any Other Bleeding Manifestations Associated Anal Pain? Fissure, abscess, hematoma, anal carcinoma Uncomplicated hemorrhoids or rectal cancer are not usually painful Any Lump at Anus?</description></item><item><title>🐢 Tracheostomy</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/anatomy/tracheostomy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/anatomy/tracheostomy/</guid><description>Surgical Anatomy of Tracheostomy: A Detailed Exploration # Tracheostomy, a surgical procedure involving the creation of an opening into the trachea through the neck, is a critical intervention in various medical contexts, from emergency airway management to long-term ventilation support. Understanding the intricate anatomy of the neck and the layered dissection involved is paramount for safe and effective tracheostomy placement.
Anatomical Considerations # 1. Surface Anatomy: Tracheostomy is typically performed between the second and fourth tracheal rings, corresponding to the level of the cricoid cartilage (C6 vertebrae level).</description></item><item><title>👒 Bladder CA</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/bladder-ca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/longcase/bladder-ca/</guid><description>Haematuria History # True Haematuria or Not # Exact Color: Dark tea color (OJ) Exclude Pseudohaematuria: Itching &amp;amp; steatorrhoea Factitious Haematuria: Munchausen’s syndrome, narcotic seeking behavior Past History # Bleeding diathesis &amp;amp; other bleeding manifestations Relation of Gross Haematuria to Urinary Stream # Initial (urethra distal to urogenital diaphragm) Total (bladder proper or upper urinary tract) Terminal (trigone/ bladder neck of prostatic urethra) Painless or Painful # Painless: Malignant but can cause pain due to clot colics Painful: Urinary tract infection or calculus, papillary necrosis, passage of clots, obstruction, loin-pain haematuria syndrome, glomerulonephritis Clots # Indicate non-glomerular bleeding Large, thick, irregular clots - bladder Small, linear clots - upper tract Passage of tissues Associated Symptoms # LUTS Fever, chills &amp;amp; rigors with loin pain or suprapubic pain Any loin pain with self-felt loin lumps (Classic triad of RCC 10% - haematuria+loin pain+loin mass) Tissue passage Vaginal or penile discharge, sexual activity Presence of urinary catheter Relation to menstruation (endometriosis) Anemic symptoms GU History # History of BPH, stone disease (Hx of GU cancers) Hx of instrumentation Hx of pelvic irradiation Aetiology for Malignancies # Smoking Occupational exposure to dye stuffs and rubber compounds Hx of travel to middle east countries (Schistosoma haematobium) Family history malignancy (bleeding diathesis + renal disease) Metastatic Features # Fitness for Sx PMHx- # PSHx- # Drug Hx- # Antiplatelets or anticoagulants, cyclophosphamide SHx- # Job(risk factors)/family Smoking/alcohol Disability/concerns Examination # General # Anemia/plethora Facial oedema/ periorbital oedema, rather than ankle edema suggest renal pathology Unilateral or bilateral ankle edema- think of Iliac vein compression in unilateral edema Bone tenderness Muscle weakness Malignant cachexia- anaemia asthenia anorexia Ask for BP Abdomen # Palpable suprapubic mass- distended bladder, anterior wall bladder tumor Ballotable renal mass Hepatomegaly Ascites DRE &amp;amp; genital Ex (non-reducing left varicocele) Summary # This 60 yrs old ASA 2, MET score &amp;gt;4, male patient with episodic visible haematuria over 3 months associated with occasional clots &amp;amp; passage of tissues.</description></item><item><title>Abdominoperineal resection</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/operative/colonsurgery/abdominoperineal-resection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/operative/colonsurgery/abdominoperineal-resection/</guid><description>Abdominopernieal resection operative notes 🏥 # Comprehensive Guide to Abdominoperineal Resection 🩺✂ # Explore the intricacies of abdominoperineal resection (APR) with our detailed guides and resources. Our step-by-step instructions ensure precision and safety in every procedure.
Essential Surgical Techniques 🛠️ # Abdominoperineal Resection (APR) 🩺🔍 # Learn the critical steps and techniques involved in performing an abdominoperineal resection, a crucial procedure for patients with rectal cancer.
Preoperative Preparation:
Patient Assessment: Detailed evaluation of the patient&amp;rsquo;s medical history and physical condition.</description></item><item><title>Principles of Surgery 🚀</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/core/principles-of-surgery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/core/principles-of-surgery/</guid><description>At me ipso nepotibus nunc celebratior genus # Tanto oblite # Copy to Clipboard {{ emojify &amp;ldquo;&amp;#x270c;&amp;#xfe0f;&amp;rdquo; }} {{ &amp;ldquo;Hello! &amp;#x1f44b;&amp;rdquo; | .RenderString }} Lorem markdownum pectora novis patenti igne sua opus aurae feras materiaque illic demersit imago et aristas questaque posset. Vomit quoque suo inhaesuro clara. Esse cumque, per referri triste. Ut exponit solisque communis in tendens vincetis agisque iamque huic bene ante vetat omina Thebae rates. Aeacus servat admonitu concidit, ad resimas vultus et rugas vultu dignamque Siphnon.</description></item><item><title>Principles of Surgery 🚀</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/principles/principles-of-surgery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/principles/principles-of-surgery/</guid><description>At me ipso nepotibus nunc celebratior genus # Tanto oblite # Copy to Clipboard {{ emojify &amp;ldquo;&amp;#x270c;&amp;#xfe0f;&amp;rdquo; }} {{ &amp;ldquo;Hello! &amp;#x1f44b;&amp;rdquo; | .RenderString }} Lorem markdownum pectora novis patenti igne sua opus aurae feras materiaque illic demersit imago et aristas questaque posset. Vomit quoque suo inhaesuro clara. Esse cumque, per referri triste. Ut exponit solisque communis in tendens vincetis agisque iamque huic bene ante vetat omina Thebae rates. Aeacus servat admonitu concidit, ad resimas vultus et rugas vultu dignamque Siphnon.</description></item><item><title>Surgery Topics 🔪✂🪡💉</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/hid_index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/hid_index/</guid><description> Welcome to Our Surgery Portal 🏥 #</description></item><item><title>Operative surgery</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/core/operative-surgery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/core/operative-surgery/</guid><description>Caput vino delphine in tamen vias # Cognita laeva illo fracta # Lorem markdownum pavent auras, surgit nunc cingentibus libet Laomedonque que est. Pastor An arbor filia foedat, ne fugit aliter, per. Helicona illas et callida neptem est Oresitrophos caput, dentibus est venit. Tenet reddite famuli praesentem fortibus, quaeque vis foret si frondes gelidos gravidae circumtulit inpulit armenta nativum.
Te at cruciabere vides rubentis manebo Maturuit in praetemptat ruborem ignara postquam habitasse Subitarum supplevit quoque fontesque venabula spretis modo Montis tot est mali quasque gravis Quinquennem domus arsit ipse Pellem turis pugnabant locavit Natus quaerere # Pectora et sine mulcere, coniuge dum tincta incurvae.</description></item><item><title>Operative surgery</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/operative/something/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/operative/something/</guid><description>Caput vino delphine in tamen vias # Cognita laeva illo fracta # Lorem markdownum pavent auras, surgit nunc cingentibus libet Laomedonque que est. Pastor An arbor filia foedat, ne fugit aliter, per. Helicona illas et callida neptem est Oresitrophos caput, dentibus est venit. Tenet reddite famuli praesentem fortibus, quaeque vis foret si frondes gelidos gravidae circumtulit inpulit armenta nativum.
Te at cruciabere vides rubentis manebo Maturuit in praetemptat ruborem ignara postquam habitasse Subitarum supplevit quoque fontesque venabula spretis modo Montis tot est mali quasque gravis Quinquennem domus arsit ipse Pellem turis pugnabant locavit Natus quaerere # Pectora et sine mulcere, coniuge dum tincta incurvae.</description></item><item><title>Operative surgery</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/principles/operative-surgery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/principles/operative-surgery/</guid><description>Caput vino delphine in tamen vias # Cognita laeva illo fracta # Lorem markdownum pavent auras, surgit nunc cingentibus libet Laomedonque que est. Pastor An arbor filia foedat, ne fugit aliter, per. Helicona illas et callida neptem est Oresitrophos caput, dentibus est venit. Tenet reddite famuli praesentem fortibus, quaeque vis foret si frondes gelidos gravidae circumtulit inpulit armenta nativum.
Te at cruciabere vides rubentis manebo Maturuit in praetemptat ruborem ignara postquam habitasse Subitarum supplevit quoque fontesque venabula spretis modo Montis tot est mali quasque gravis Quinquennem domus arsit ipse Pellem turis pugnabant locavit Natus quaerere # Pectora et sine mulcere, coniuge dum tincta incurvae.</description></item><item><title>Creating a New Theme</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid><description>Introduction # This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description></item><item><title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid><description>Move static content to static # Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description></item><item><title>🎽 Other</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/other/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/other/</guid><description> Miscellaneous # AAA Young hypertensive</description></item><item><title>👋 Hand</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/hand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/hand/</guid><description>Hand # Pointing index Mallet finger Wasting of small muscles Wrist drop Wrist lumps ganglion Claw hand CTS De Quervain&amp;rsquo;s Tenosynovitis Principles of hand examination # Principles include includes inspection palpation Feel Move Range of movement Ease of movement Inspection invisible scars over common surgical sites contour of the hand discoloration and sinuses. Also check muscle wasting, Thenar eminence Hypothenar eminence dorsal side of hand the muscle bulk between metacarpal bones which is interosseous muscle Palpation.</description></item><item><title>👠 Foot</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/foot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/foot/</guid><description> Foot # Halux valgus Ingrowing toenail Bunion</description></item><item><title>🤸‍♀️ Limb</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/limb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/limb/</guid><description> Limb # Foot ulcer Amputation stump AV malformation popliteal fossa Neuropathic sole ulcer Varicose veins Digital gangrene / Dry gangrene Unilateral limb swelling Chronic limb ulcer Pseudoaneurysm / AVF</description></item><item><title>🦕 Neck</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/neck/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/vascular/neck/</guid><description> Neck # Anterior triangle lump (Carotid triangle / sternomastoid) Carotid body tumour</description></item><item><title>🪲 Abdominal Bay</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/abdomen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/abdomen/</guid><description> Abdominal short cases # Incisional hernia abdominal mass Liver mets, ascites, Enterocutaneous fistula PUH Epigastric / RHC mass Liver Ca, Pancreas CA, Pseudocyst, Gastric CA RIF / LIF mass Urinary fistula</description></item><item><title>🦿 Joint</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/joints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/orthopaedic/joints/</guid><description> Major joints # Genu valgum Knee lumps CDH Limping Child Slipped upper femoral epiphysis CTEV Elbow lumps</description></item><item><title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/goisforlovers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/goisforlovers/</guid><description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Hugo</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugoisforlovers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugoisforlovers/</guid><description>Step 1. Install Hugo # Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs # Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/signs/a-signs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/signs/a-signs/</guid><description>Signs starts with A # 1. Aaron’s Sign # A sensation of pain and/or distress in the epigastric or precordial region on pressure over McBurney’s point in appendicitis.
1. Aaron’s Sign # A sensation of pain and/or distress in the epigastric or precordial region on pressure over McBurney’s point in appendicitis.
2. Abadie’s Sign # Charles Abadie: Spasm of levator palpebrae superioris muscle—a sign of Graves’ disease. Jean Abadie: Insensibility of Achilles tendon to pressure, seen in tabes dorsalis.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/signs/b-sign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/signs/b-sign/</guid><description>Signs starts with B # 9. Babinski’s Sign (Not synonymous with Babinski’s Reflex) # a. Loss or weakening of the Achilles tendon reflex in sciatica. This sign helps distinguish true sciatica from hysterical sciatica. 9. Babinski’s Sign (Not synonymous with Babinski’s Reflex) # a. Loss or weakening of the Achilles tendon reflex in sciatica. This sign helps distinguish true sciatica from hysterical sciatica. b. In hemiplegia, the contraction of the platysma muscle on the healthy side is more pronounced than on the affected side.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/triangles-in-surgery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/pages/triangles-in-surgery/</guid><description>Triangles in Surgery # 1. Hesselbach’s Triangle # Borders: Medial: Rectus sheath Superolateral: Inferior epigastric artery Inferior: Inguinal ligament Importance: Helps in differentiating direct from indirect hernias. 2. Bryant’s Triangle # Formation: Patient lies supine Line 1: From the anterior superior iliac spine vertically down to the bed Line 2: From the tip of the greater trochanter to join Line 1 at right angles Line 3: From the anterior superior iliac spine to the tip of the greater trochanter Importance: Diminution in the length of Line 2 indicates upward displacement of the greater trochanter.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/hidden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/hidden/</guid><description>This page is hidden in menu # Quondam non pater est dignior ille Eurotas # Latent te facies # Lorem markdownum arma ignoscas vocavit quoque ille texit mandata mentis ultimus, frementes, qui in vel. Hippotades Peleus pennas conscia cuiquam Caeneus quas.
Pater demittere evincitque reddunt Maxime adhuc pressit huc Danaas quid freta Soror ego Luctus linguam saxa ultroque prior Tatiumque inquit Saepe liquitur subita superata dederat Anius sudor Cum honorum Latona # O fallor in sustinui iussorum equidem.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/lipoma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/surgery/shortcase/skin/lipoma/</guid><description>Lipoma # Examination findings of lipoma</description></item></channel></rss>